HIEF PRODUCT MANAGER · BUILDING PHYSICS, DIGITAL TWINS, MASTERPLAN

Glasgow, UK

□ (+44) 7514744121 | www.virtual-climate.com | Imagieroguida | www.virtual-climate.com

"Fighting Climate Change by digitizing the built environment."



Summary

I am a multi-faceted engineer with broad experience in a variety of sustainability related projects in the built environment, now focusing on digital twins, urban modelling and building operations via product management and software development.

I bring 20 years of experience in sustainability and in particular in green buildings, from concept to construction to operation. Currently working at IES Ltd. as Chief Product Manager where my responsibilities span from idea generation to product launch and commercialization.

Co-founder of Virtual Climate Ltd., a software company dedicated to democratize access to complex outdoor comfort analysis and computation fluid dynamics on the cloud for small to medium size organizations.

I am focused on the goal and able to remove the noise to achieve the target outcome. I excel at synthesizing different complex requirements in a coherent solution, and I am not afraid of taking calculated risks and make decisions.

Work Experience

IES Ltd. Glasgow, UK

ASSOCIATE DIRECTOR — CHIEF PRODUCT MANAGER

Jan. 2020 — Present

- Man responsibilities: product specification, product strategy, implementation management, customers liaisons.
- Coordinated various products in one single software solution.
- Defined and formalised the product vision in line with company mission.
- Managed several R&D software projects originating completely new products or improving existing ones.
- Supported Marketing and Sales in presentations, demos and communication of product vision to existing and prospective customers.
- Defined projects scope, goals and deliverables to ensure alignment with overall company and product vision.
- Lead the UI and UX team to develop a consistent design language across the product lines.
- Cloud evangelist Instrumental in company (on going) transition to cloud and SaaS.
- Continuously monitoring technology and competitor landscape to keep abreast of new trends and requirements
- Spoken to tens of target customers and users

PRODUCT MANAGER Oct. 2016 – Dec. 2019

- Supported Marketing and Sales in demos and presentations.
- Gathered feedback from users and translated it in user stories.
- **Trent Basin Digital Twin** Project Manager and engineering technical lead Digital twin for a residential development in Nottingham. Developed an interactive platform that enables the community to visualise energy data in real-time.
- Stirling Council Smart Hub Developed a centralised smart energy platform to collect, monitor and manage energy and renewables data for the council building portfolio. The project originated a new product now called the Command Centre. Developed independent data layer between several customer's systems (Building Management System, utilities websites and ftp servers, REST APIs) and historian database.
- Product manager and domain expert for urban design and building operation product line.

Virtual Climate Ltd. Glasgow, UK

CO-FOUNDER & SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2020 — Present

Jun. 2015 - Sep. 2016

- Developed a desktop application in Ruby/Python/C with web frontend in HTML/JavaScript for outdoor comfort analysis by using Computational Fluid Dynamic on AWS clusters. Additional AWS services: EC2, S3, EFS, AWS APIs.
- Landed a contract with established consultancy in UK for the use of the tool for their projects.

Sabbatical Asia, US, Europe

BUILDING PHYSICS AND SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

• Spent one year travelling and developing what has now become a commercial product.

• Delivered 3 pilot projects in the Middle East, Hong Kong and Europe to test to product market fit and features.

OCTOBER 18, 2021 GLASGOW · UNITED KINGDOM

WSP Middle East

Associate

Dubai, UAE

Jan. 2012 – May. 2015

Started as a senior consultant and left as Associate.

- Managed the building physics team within the Sustainability and Energy group. Focused on building physics and computer modeling of the built environment.
- Championed computer modelling during concept and detailed design to management and engineering teams.
- Delivered BULGARI Island Dubai CFD, building energy and outdoor comfort analysis.
- Delivered Opera District Dubai outdoor comfort and wind analysis.
- Delivered simulation based Building Regulations in the Philippines, Vietnam and Bangladesh in collaboration with International Finance Corporation (World Bank)

Sefaira (now Trimble)

London, UK

PRINCIPAL BUILDING ENGINEER

Jul. 2010 - Dec. 2012

- Contributed to shape the initial concept and implementation of the core software for the company during the startup phase
- Advised architects on energy efficiency and passive design.
- Joined as employee number five and brought well needed experience from the industry and user perspective.

Max Fordham London, UK

ENVIRONMENTAL ENGINEER

Jun. 2005 – Jun. 2010

- Appointed initially as a Building Physicist, subsequently developed this role to become a key figure in the modelling department of the company.
- Promoted as a Project Engineer in 2008 and Partner in 2009.
- Contributed to the delivery of various prestigious projects such as the London Olympics water polo arena and several Zaha Hadid buildings.
- Key skills: building energy modelling, computational fluid dynamics, mechanical design.

Previous experiences

Rome/Milan, Italy

VARIOUS ROLES

Sep. 2000 - Jun. 2005

- Italia Lavoro Ltd. Renewables feasibility studies.
- Arcadia Software consultancy in Customer Releationship Management software
- Compulsory Military Service

Certifications & Awards

2015 **Winner**, Middle East Green Building Research award

Dubai, UAE

2011 Member, CIBSE - Chartered Institution of Building Service Engineers

UK

Education

Politecnico di Bari Italy

M.S. IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING AND COMPUTATIONAL FLUID DYNAMICS

1993 - 2000

• Spent a year in Manchester at Manchester Metropolitan University to write thesis

Skills

Product Management Agile methodologies, scrum, demos, domain expert

Soft Skills Client liaison, presentations, team engagement **Management** Mentoring, tutoring, project management, support

Programming Intermediate: Ruby, Basic: Python, C, JavaScript, HTML

Computer modelling Energy modeling, computational fluid dynamics,

Work related hobbies Electronics, IoT, coding

Languages Italian, English